I'm late. I have to hurry.
要遲到了，得快點了
Oh, no. My watch isn't working.
天啊，我的錶竟然停了
Sorry I'm late.
久等了
Mai! You're late.
小舞，妳太晚了吧？
I couldn't decide what to wear.
抱歉，我選衣服選了好久
How do I look?
我看起來怎麼樣？
You look great.
-很好
White looks pure and innocent.
白色清純無瑕
It's rare to see you join a mixer party.
真是難得，小舞竟然來參加聯誼
-Hey, Mai just broke up recently. -Did you?
-小舞不是才剛分手嗎？ -是嗎？
Forget that. I'm already 27. I thought I should find someone soon.
別說這個，我都27歲了 是時候找新的對象了
You can count on me.
交給我吧
Today I invited mature men who are thinking seriously about their future.
今天我邀請的 都是認真計畫將來的成熟男性
There's a doctor, lawyer, and a president.
是啊，有醫生、有律師，還有社長呢
That sounds perfect.
簡直完美
UNIVERSITY ALUMNI REUNION
（櫻東大學經濟系校友會）
How are you?
-好久不見
-Look at your forehead. -I know.
-你的頭髮也開始禿了啊 -是啊
Hey, Soma!
相馬
-Excuse me. -Hey!
失陪，喂
Aoi! How have you been?
青井，好久不見啊
When did we see each other last?
我們上次見面是什麼時候啊？
It's been ten years.
也有十年了吧？
That's a long time.
那麼久啦？
How is your work?
工作怎麼樣了？
I'm sure you got promoted.
應該混得不錯吧？
I became independent five years ago.
這個嘛，我五年前自己出來創業了
This is my job now.
現在在幹這個
Hey! You're the president of an IT company?
你居然是科技公司社長了啊？
You have an office in that Osaki skyscraper?
而且辦公室在大崎的摩天大樓？
That's great.
好厲害啊
It's still waiting to take off.
公司才剛起步呢
How about you?
你怎麼樣了？
Are you still a banker?
還在銀行上班嗎？
Yes. Here you go.
是啊，給你
Headquarters.
總部？
That sounds great. You must be right on track.
很厲害啊，應該是扶搖直上了吧？
Well, not really.
這個嘛，也不是這麼好啦
Long time no see. You haven't changed at all.
好久不見，你真是一點兒都沒變呢
You came here?
妳來了啊？
DIRECTOR/MD-PHD, LAWYER
（院長、醫學博士、律師）
PRESIDENT
（社長）
Hello.
你們好
-Hello.
-妳們好 -你們好
They look very old.
怎麼感覺都是大叔啊？
But they have the right titles.
但是頭銜是真的啊
Yes.
的確
I am Tanaka, 46 years old, and I'm a divorcee.
我叫田中，46歲，離過一次婚
My wife passed away two years ago.
我的妻子在兩年前去世了
I am looking for someone who I can build a happy family with.
我是想找能一起組織快樂家庭的伴侶
So this is what they mean by men who are "mature and serious about marriage."
所以他們就是 “認真計畫將來的成熟男性”啊？
You look good.
你看起來過得不錯
Thank you.
嗯，還可以
What's wrong, Soma?
怎麼了，相馬？
You look awkward. You know her well.
這麼冷淡，你們又不是不熟
I know.
也是
How long have you not seen each other for?
你們倆多久沒見了？
Five years?
五年？
Nearly six years.
差不多六年了吧？
I see. No wonder we became old.
這樣啊，難怪我們都這麼老了
We?
我們？
That rude attitude of yours has not changed at all.
你這種失禮的個性還真是一點都沒變
Ouch.
好痛
I'm sorry. My friend introduced them to me.
抱歉啊，是朋友介紹給我的
But I didn't do enough research.
不過，我也沒做好事先調查
This is all part of the experience.
算了，這種事也是難免的
-Don't worry. We can try again. -Yes.
-別介意，下次會更好的 -好
Sorry.
抱歉
See you later.
那下次見
-Bye.
-再見
What time is it now?
現在幾點了？
Mr. Soma.
相馬
Hanasaki.
花咲
Wait…
等等…
Hanasaki, wait!
花咲，等等
-Don't jump to conclusions. -I didn't know you had a date. Congrats!
-妳不要誤會啊 -我都不知道你有約會對象呢，恭喜
-That's not it. -Don't be shy.
-不是啦 -不要害羞嘛
Hello.
妳好
Hello. I'm Hanasaki. I am nothing but his colleague.
妳好，我叫花咲 只是相馬的下屬而已
I am Yumi Ishihara. Nice to meet you.
我叫石原由美，初次見面
I…
啊…
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
-我是… -讓你們久等了
-It wasn't a date? -I said not.
-你們不是約會嗎？ -都說不是了
I am his ex-wife.
我是相馬的前妻
I see, his ex…
這樣啊，是…
Ex-wife?
前妻？
I see.
原來如此
Nice to meet you. I am Mai Hanasaki.
初次見面，我叫花咲舞
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
-乾杯
Now Mr. Soma,
相馬
tell us how you felt seeing your ex-wife at the reunion.
請說說在校友會上與前妻重逢的感想
Don't make fun of me. Stop it already.
別鬧了，妳真煩
How can I not? It was a rare chance to see the two of you together.
畢竟我目擊了你們倆同框的珍貴一幕 怎麼能不鬧呢？
Soma liked Yumi since we were university students.
相馬從大學的時候 就一直很喜歡由美了啊
But he proposed to her over ten years after we had graduated.
但我們畢業十年後他才求婚
I didn't know.
我都不知道呢
Mr. Soma, you're a very devoted person.
相馬，沒想到你還是挺專一的嘛
-Here. -You're rather romantic, huh.
-給你 -居然是個浪漫的人呢
See? This is why I told you not to say anything.
所以我才叫你不要那麼多廢話啊
-Can I have one more? -Yes.
-能再來一瓶嗎？ -好的
The three of us used to go out for drinks like this.
那時候我們三個經常這樣一起喝酒呢
It sounds like the good old days. Here you go.
真是滿滿的青春氣息啊
Thanks.
-給你 -謝謝
Is that your wife? You have cute children.
這位是你太太嗎？孩子們也好可愛啊
She's three and he's two. They're such rascals.
女兒三歲，兒子兩歲，搗蛋鬼兩枚
I'm sure your wife has her hands full.
你太太一定很辛苦吧？
Yes. So I try to go home early to spend time with my family.
是啊，所以我都盡量早點回家陪家人
Prioritizing work is out of date now.
這年頭的人都不再只顧著工作了
You have a great job and a great family.
你真是事業和家庭都一帆風順啊
-You've always been stable. -Compared to you.
-跟以前一樣踏實穩重 -跟你比起來，確實如此
Shut up.
閉嘴啦
Why did you get divorced, Mr. Soma?
相馬，你當初為什麼會離婚呢？
Do you think this is the right moment to ask that?
這時候問這種問題合適嗎？
Because I got transferred…
就是我當時被調職嘛
Oh, when the Section Chief of the Finance Department
對了，就是丸之內分行的融資課課長
pushed his responsibility on you and got you transferred, right?
要你揹黑鍋 再把你調走的那件事，對吧？
Hey, Mai!
喂，小舞
You really like to rub salt in the wound.
妳還真喜歡在別人傷口上撒鹽啊
Sorry.
抱歉
I didn't know that. You had a hard time.
我都不知道呢，你也不容易啊
So I fell off the corporate ladder a while ago.
所以我早就沒晉升的希望了
But what a shame to break up with such a beautiful lady.
但是，和那麼美的女人分開 還真是可惜啊
-You won't have a second chance. -It's not for you to decide.
-你可找不著下一個了 -這由不得妳說
She's happily remarried, so it's all good.
她現在再婚了，過得很幸福 這樣就好了
Then you're the only one that's lonely.
那就只剩下你一個人孤獨終老了
Same as you.
彼此彼此吧？
I'm not the same.
我可不一樣
-Let's drink tonight. -Sure.
-今晚不醉不歸 -好
Mai, you said you ran into Mr. Soma, but what were you doing there?
小舞，妳說妳碰巧遇到了相馬 那妳在那裡幹嘛？
I had dinner with my girlfriends.
就是跟女生朋友吃飯啊
She went to a mixer party, but she said it wasn't good.
她是去聯誼的，可是都不怎麼樣
A mixer party? You attend those things?
聯誼？妳會參加這種活動啊？
Well, it's not a mixer party but…
與其說是聯誼，還不如…
Of course I go to mixer parties. I'm 27.
去個聯誼有問題嗎？我都27歲了
You're right. Of course you would.
也對，是該去聯誼了
What a hassle. You didn't have to tell him that.
我爸真是煩死了，都怪你亂說話啦
I just copied you.
我是跟妳學的啊
I don't want to talk about that terrible mixer party.
那個可怕的聯誼會，我才不想再提呢
It's all Mr. Soma's fault.
都怪那個相馬
Did you drink too much?
喝多了嗎？
Yes, I ended up drinking too much…
是啊，後半場喝得太興奮…
Executive Director Shindo.
真藤常務
Good morning.
早安
I remember you were being interviewed for the company newsletter the other day.
妳前幾天不是接受了 《社內報導》的採訪嗎？
-Yes, but… -This is the one.
-對，可是… -就是這個
Here.
在這裡
THIS MONTH'S WOMAN OF TOKYO DAIICHI
（《東京第一銀行本月女性》）
It was much smaller than planned.
比預期的小了很多
I see. Work hard.
這樣啊，繼續加油
Thank you very much.
謝謝
This is only for Managers.
這是董事專用電梯
I'm sorry.
抱歉
You are laughing too much.
你們笑得太過分了啦
Don't worry. It means…
沒關係，所以妳剛才…
you're being talked about.
妳可成了話題的中心啊
He is right, Ms. Hanasaki.
是啊，花咲
Even if it's only a small article, it's still a good memory.
再小的版面也是一個很好的紀念啊
Stop it, both of you.
你們兩個夠了哦
I have a phone call. Be quiet.
電話響了，安靜點
Branch Inspection. Yes.
這裡是分行稽核班，是
It was nice meeting you yesterday.
昨晚真是多謝關照
Please wait one moment.
請稍等
Mr. Soma, it's Mr. Aoi.
相馬，是青井先生打來的電話
Aoi?
青井打來的？
Soma? Sorry to call you during work.
相馬，抱歉打擾你工作
I had a lot of fun yesterday.
我昨晚真的很高興
Yeah. What's up?
是嗎？你找我有什麼事？
What? Loan?
什麼？融資？
I was thinking about getting one recently.
對，我最近在考慮融資
If I'm going to get one, I want to get it at your bank.
想說既然要申請 不如就找你們銀行好了
This is a good chance.
可能也是天意吧？
I see. Thanks. It's great news for our company too.
這樣啊，謝謝你 這對我們銀行來說也是好事
If you get a loan contract, you'll get to take credit for it, right?
如果談得成融資的合約 你也能記功，對吧？
You're a busybody as usual.
你還是那麼喜歡替人操心呢
Your company is in Osaki, right?
你的公司在大崎，對吧？
It's in the Jounan area.
是城南區吧？
That's great. I want to introduce you to someone in the Finance Department.
正好，我可以給你介紹 那邊分行的融資課員工
Sounds great.
那就拜託你了
-I'll be waiting for your call. -Okay. Bye.
-我等你的電話哦 -好，再見
Are we going to finance Mr. Aoi's company?
青井先生的公司 要找我們銀行融資嗎？
Yes. I guess he was thinking of applying for a loan.
是啊，他說之前就在找銀行融資
That's great.
那挺好的啊
-He's the one that owns his company? -Yes.
-是那位科技公司社長嗎？ -是的
Who are you going to introduce him to?
你打算介紹誰給他啊？
Remember that uncommonly passionate man in the Finance Department?
記得那個罕見的熱血融資業務員嗎？
He taught me all about loans.
他嚴厲地教導了我融資的基礎呢
-Mr. Matsuki? -Correct.
-松木先生 -沒錯
This is working out so well.
這可真是緣分啊
Yes.
是啊
DIGITAL BLUE COMPANY
（藍色數位公司）
CREDIT FOR INCOME TAX
（所得稅抵免）
RESTAURANT HANASAKI ONE WEEK LATER
（花咲居酒屋，一週後）
Thank you very much.
真是謝謝你
Thanks to you, I'm about to get a new loan contract.
託你的福，我才拿到了新的融資業務
Good for you.
太好了
-Yes. -Enough with the greetings. Sit down.
-是啊 -不用客套了，坐吧
Sit here.
坐這邊
Thanks.
謝謝
I can sit next to Ms. Hanasaki?
我可以坐花咲小姐的旁邊嗎？
Sure. Please.
當然了，坐吧
Thank you.
好，不好意思
-Let's have a toast. -Sure.
-先乾一杯 -好的
Cheers!
-乾杯
Congratulations.
恭喜你啊
I've been having a hard time meeting my sales target these days.
我最近的業績都沒達標，正煩惱呢
So thank you very much for giving me a chance.
真的很感謝你給我這麼好的機會
No, all I did was introduce him to your manager.
別這麼說 我也只是把他介紹給你的經理而已
You were recommending Mr. Matsuki to the Gotanda Branch Manager.
你明明是對五反田分行經理說 一定要給松木先生處理的
Good for you, Mr. Matsuki. This is from me.
太好了，松木，我提前祝賀你
You like Japanese-style omelet, right?
你喜歡的醬汁雞蛋卷
Thank you.
那我就不客氣了
-This is delicious. -I can tell you love it.
-好好吃 -看得出你很喜歡
It was a great office.
話說，他們的辦公室太棒了
It's only five years ago that he launched his
青井先生五年前
company, Digital Blue, after leaving a major IT communications company.
才辭去大型通訊公司的工作 創辦了這家藍色數位公司
It was not long before he made a five-billion-yen profit. He's amazing.
公司成立不久後 盈利就達50億日元，真的太厲害了
There's a high chance the loan will get approved, right?
這麼說，融資很可能被批准，對吧？
Yes. All I have to do is send the proposal document.
是的，我只需要遞交提案書就行了
The loan is this much.
融資金額是這麼多
Fifty million yen? That's reasonable.
五千萬日元嗎？蠻合理的
No! It's 500 million yen.
不對，是五億日元
Five hundred million yen?
五億日元？
That's quite a lot.
真的很多呢
-Matsuki, work hard. -Yes.
-那松木，你得好好幹了 -是
I want to ask you a favor.
有件事我想請你幫個忙
Will you check the proposal document for me tomorrow?
能請你明天幫我看一下提案書嗎？
-Proposal document? -Yes.
-提案書？ -是的
I would like you to check it before I send it to the Manager.
我希望你能過目一下，我再交給經理
I see. You're having a hard time with it, aren't you?
這樣啊，看來你是想讓我一起操心呢
Can you tell?
被你發現了？
Okay. I will check it if you want.
好吧，你要的話，就幫你看一下吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Mr. Soma is respected more than I thought.
相馬比我想像的更受人尊敬呢
You just have no respect for your boss.
只有妳不尊敬妳的上司，好嗎？
DIGITAL BLUE INC.
（藍色數位公司）
How does he plan to use the 500 million yen?
他打算怎麼利用那五億？
Research and development.
研究和開發
He'll use that for a cloud-based
他會用那筆錢來開發
customer information database and application development.
雲端化顧客資訊資料庫和應用程式
It's hard to understand.
都聽不懂呢
I know. IT related work is very difficult.
是啊，資訊科技相關的行業很複雜
We have no benchmark for novelty, originality and product value.
他們注重創新、獨創以及商品價值
-It's the bank's weak spot. -Yes.
-我們銀行並沒有評價這些的標準 -是的
We have more experience in evaluating existing industries
銀行目前為止 都是評價製造業或服務業
such as manufacturing or service.
這一類的傳統行業
The point is how to evaluate the technology of Aoi's company.
所以關鍵就在於 如何評價青井公司的技術
What's the sharing rate with other banks?
和其他銀行分擔風險的比率呢？
We won't be sharing it.
不分擔
Are we going to finance the development cost by ourselves?
那些開發費用 全額由我們銀行來支援嗎？
Yes.
是的
Until now, their main bank was Hakusui Bank.
他們一直以來主要與白水銀行合作
But he wants to take this chance and move to our bank.
想藉由這次機會徹底轉到我們銀行
He has high expectations of us.
他很看重我們呢
-This is a good document. -Really?
-這個提案書做得不錯 -真的嗎？
Just give a concrete explanation about their future business plans
只需要再具體解釋公司將來的計畫
and it will be more convincing.
應該會更有說服力
Okay.
好的
Thank you very much.
謝謝
Ms. Hanasaki, I will come again.
花咲小姐，我會再來的
Good luck.
辛苦你了
I'm glad to see that things are going well for Mr. Matsuki.
太好了，松木先生看起來一切順利呢
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Something bothers me.
有件事我想不通
The loan from Hakusui Bank wasn't reduced at all.
白水銀行發放的融資金額沒有減少
Isn't that because they are expanding their business?
應該是因為他們正在擴展業務吧？
Development companies usually reduce their loans
像那種開發型的企業
as their business performance gets better.
通常會在業績變好之後減少公司貸款
I see. That's how it goes.
這樣啊
I'm sure there's nothing to worry about.
不過，應該沒什麼好擔心的吧？
Mr. Soma?
相馬？
I'm going to step out.
我出去一下
Finish the report for Mukoujima Branch.
向島分行的報告書就拜託妳了
Where are you going, Mr. Soma?
等等，相馬，你要去哪？
28F DIGITAL BLUE INC.
（28樓，藍色數位公司）
PRESIDENT SHOUICHI AOI
（藍色數位公司，社長青井省一）
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-不好意思 -是
Do you know when the floors below Digital Blue became vacant?
請問藍色數位公司下面那幾層樓 是從什麼時候開始空著的？
About two months ago.
大約兩個月前吧？
Originally, this company used three floors.
這家公司原本是三個樓層的
I see. Thank you.
原來如此，謝謝妳
I wonder where Mr. Soma went.
相馬到底去了哪裡啊？
Excuse me.
失禮了
Bankrupt?
破產？
THE COMPANY IS DOWNSIZING. I WAS LAID OFF…
（公司正在縮減規模 我被解雇了…）
I HAVE TO LOOK FOR A JOB NOW
（縮減規模）
What is this?
怎麼回事啊？
Hello.
歡迎光臨
Sorry to call you out so suddenly.
真抱歉，突然叫妳出來
Knowing you, there must be an important reason why you called me.
你一打給我 我就知道你一定是有什麼重要的事情
It is about Aoi.
是有關青井的事
His wife is your junior, right?
他的妻子是妳的後輩，對吧？
Yes. I introduced Saori to him.
對，是我介紹沙織給他的
Have you seen her recently? Do you know anything about Aoi?
妳最近有見過她嗎？ 有沒有聽到什麼關於青井的事？
Why do you want to know all of a sudden?
你怎麼突然問這些？
His company is applying for a loan from our bank right now.
他的公司在向我們銀行申請融資
So I wanted to know.
只是想問問而已
I see.
原來如此
I go out for lunch with Saori once in a while.
我偶爾會跟沙織一起吃午餐、聊聊天
But I haven't seen her lately.
不過最近倒是沒見面呢
I see.
這樣啊
You keep worrying about other people,
你總是為別人操心
but are you all right?
那你自己怎麼樣啊？
Do you have any plans to remarry?
沒有再婚的打算嗎？
I was told that I won't have a second chance since I lost you.
不久前，才有人對我說 我找不著像妳那麼好的人呢
Says who?
誰這麼說你啊？
How about you?
妳呢？
Are you happy?
過得幸福嗎？
Yes. Since I don't have a child, I sometimes get envious of Saori
嗯，我們沒有孩子
when I hear her talk about her children.
所以有時聽到沙織說起她孩子 我就會有點羡慕
But I'm happy as long as my husband and I can stay happy and healthy.
不過，只要我們兩夫妻和睦健康 就很滿足了
That's more than enough.
這比什麼都重要
Oh, I remember…
我想起來了
She said that Aoi comes home late every day.
她有說，青井每天都很晚才回家
He rarely eats dinner with his children.
很少和孩子們一起吃晚餐
She was saying that things didn't used to be like that.
說青井以前不會這樣
I try to go home early and spend time with my family.
所以我都盡量早點回家陪家人
She says Aoi doesn't talk about his business at home.
她說青井從不在家裡提工作的事
But being busy must be a good sign.
不過，忙著工作應該是件好事吧？
Thanks.
謝謝
-I'll call you again. -Hey.
-我會再聯繫妳的 -要走了嗎？
Matsuki, are you at the branch right now?
松木，你現在在分行嗎？
Hanasaki, why are you here?
花咲，妳怎麼會在這裡？
You have doubts about Mr. Aoi's company, don't you?
你在懷疑青井先生的公司吧？
I researched it too.
我也調查了
…IN TROUBLE… GOES BANKRUPT
（那家公司有困難 破產只是時間的問題）
Digital Blue downsized their company two months ago.
藍色數位公司 在兩個月前縮小了公司的規模
That itself might not be so uncommon,
這本來也不是什麼大不了的事
but the problem is that Mr. Aoi is hiding that fact. Right?
問題就在於青井先生有心隱瞞此事
This is their financial statement.
這是他們的財務報告
What's wrong?
有什麼問題嗎？
Why did you want to see this document in secret?
你為什麼要我瞞著經理 讓你偷偷看這個啊？
Just to double check. Right, Mr. Soma?
只是想看看而已，對吧，相馬？
Matsuki.
松木
-Did you make a copy of this by yourself? -No.
-這份報告是你複印的嗎？ -不是
Then who?
那是誰複印的？
I called him to ask for the financial statements.
我打電話跟他們公司要的
The copy was already made when I visited his company,
我去他們公司進行面談的當天 就已經準備好了
and President Aoi gave it to me directly.
是青井社長親手給我的
Then you didn't check the original?
所以你沒有看過原件？
No.
沒有
That's not good.
糟了
Is there a problem?
有什麼問題嗎？
As a general rule, we have to borrow the tax documents once,
原則來說 我們應該把對方的稅務文件拿回來
and make a copy of them at the bank.
在銀行內部進行複印
Is that to prevent fabrication?
是為了防止偽造嗎？
Right.
沒錯
Fabrication? Wait a minute, Mr. Soma.
偽造？等等，相馬先生
What are you suspicious of?
你到底在懷疑什麼？
He is your friend from university, isn't he?
青井先生不是你的大學同學嗎？
I am not sure yet.
我也不太確定
But Aoi is hiding something from us.
不過，青井肯定在隱瞞什麼
Matsuki. Please wait before submitting the proposal document to the Manager.
松木，能不能先不要送出提案書？
The Branch Manager will get mad.
經理會生氣的
He told me to submit it as soon as possible.
他已經在催了
Please.
拜託了
What are you going to do, Mr. Soma?
相馬，你想做什麼？
I will ask the companies listed here about their transactions with Digital Blue.
我會去拜訪這上面的公司 問問他們與藍色數位公司的交易內容
They won't tell you.
他們不會隨便告訴你吧？
If it's companies that our bank deals with,
如果那些公司跟我們銀行有合作的話
I might get some information through the Finance Department.
我可以向融資課拿資料
Either way, I will do what I can.
反正能做的都試試看吧
President. How about the payment to the data center?
社長 向資料中心支付的事情怎麼樣了？
Don't worry.
別擔心
I will get funding before the due date.
截止日期之前會拿到資金的
-Don't worry. -Okay.
-沒事的 -好的
According to the documents, your company paid 30 million yen to Digital Blue.
根據資料，貴公司向藍色數位 支付了3000萬日元，對吧？
Thirty million yen?
3000萬日元？
That must be some mistake.
應該是搞錯了吧？
A mistake?
搞錯了？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
We only paid five million yen.
我們只支付了500萬
Then what about the payment of 15 million yen?
那麼，這1500萬的付款呢？
We paid three million yen at most. Look here.
我們最多只付了300萬 你們可以看看
DIGITAL BLUE INC ANNUAL PAYMENT 2,916,000 YEN
（藍色數位公司 年付291萬6千日元）
We stopped using that company last year.
我們去年就沒再跟那家公司合作了
Stopped?
沒再合作了？
May I ask you why?
請問是為什麼？
I hear their business is in dire straits.
我聽說他們經營不善，陷入財務困境
Now it's clear that Digital Blue's business is deteriorating,
很明顯藍色數位的生意每況愈下
so we will not be able to finance them.
我們不能提供貸款
That financial statement was fabricated too, right?
這份財務報告也是偽造的吧？
This is terrible.
太過分了
Isn't this fraud?
這不是在詐騙嗎？
Why did Aoi do this?
青井先生為什麼要這麼做？
-Money. -What?
-為了錢 -什麼？
He tried to pull money from Tokyo Daiichi Bank
他想利用假文件向東京第一銀行
using manipulated documents.
取得資金
For 500 million yen.
五億日元
That's unforgivable.
真是不可原諒
He used his friend too.
連朋友都利用
Matsuki.
松木
I'm sorry.
對不起
Mr. Soma.
相馬先生
I should have researched it, before introducing him.
我應該好好調查後再介紹給你的
It's all my fault.
都是我不好
I caused huge trouble for you and the Gotanda Branch.
給你和五反田分行添了那麼大的麻煩
Please don't say that.
請別這麼說
You're not the one to blame, Mr. Soma. It's Mr. Aoi.
這事不應該怪你，都是青井先生的錯
I will go see Mr. Aoi.
我去找他
Please wait, Matsuki.
等一下，松木
Let me go.
讓我去吧
What?
什麼？
I think…
我想
he had reasons for doing this.
他這麼做一定是有苦衷的
I'm sure he's dealing with a serious problem.
可能是…遇到了很大的困難
Why are you covering for him?
你為什麼還要袒護他呢？
Mr. Aoi deceived you to get money.
他為了錢欺騙你啊
He is not your friend.
這算什麼朋友？
He is my friend.
他是我的朋友
Even if he betrayed me,
就算他背叛了我
he is still my friend.
他還是我的朋友
Please.
拜託了
Mr. Matsuki!
松木先生
The proposal document.
這個提案書
Um…
那個…
I'm sorry about the new loan contract.
融資業務的事鬧成這樣，真的很遺憾
No. I will get another one by myself.
沒關係，我會努力找業務的
I'm more worried about Mr. Soma.
其實，我比較擔心相馬先生
Yes.
是啊
See you.
我走了
Hello, Ms. Hanasaki.
妳好，花咲小姐，對吧？
Yes.
是的
He forgot this when I met him today.
我白天和相馬見面時，他忘了這個
I called him many times, but he won't answer.
我打給他好多次都沒人接
Will you return this to Soma for me?
能請妳幫我還給他嗎？
Yes. Thank you.
好的，謝謝妳
I guess there is something going on with Aoi?
是不是青井那邊出了什麼狀況？
He's usually very calm, but he is having a hard time right now.
相馬平時都很冷靜的 現在卻非常煩惱
I see.
這樣啊
-May I ask you something? -Yes?
-我能問妳一件事嗎？ -可以啊
What kind of friendship did Mr. Aoi and Mr. Soma have?
相馬和青井先生的關係怎麼樣？
They were really good friends.
他們兩個是很好的朋友
They have different personalities,
雖然個性完全不同
but they got along well and motivated each other.
但是他們很投緣，一直激勵彼此
I see.
原來如此
When we decided to get married,
我和相馬決定結婚時
Aoi was happier than anyone else.
青井比誰都高興
But we all got busy and didn't see each other for a while.
後來我們各自忙碌了起來 就有些疏遠了
And then we ended up divorcing.
沒過多久，我們也離婚了
They hadn't seen each other for about ten years.
他們大概有十年沒見了吧？
But I'm sure they always thought of each other.
不過，我相信他們還是一直想著對方
I guess Mr. Aoi is a special friend to Mr. Soma.
對相馬來說 青井先生一定是很特別的朋友吧？
I've never seen Mr. Soma look so down.
我沒看過相馬那麼失落呢
But I can't be of any help to him.
但我卻什麼忙都幫不上
He can be sensitive, despite how he comes across.
別看他那樣，其實他是很脆弱的
I couldn't do anything for him either.
我也做不了什麼
During his most difficult time…
在他最痛苦的時候
TRANSFER NOTICE
（轉職通知）
All he needed me to do was to support him by staying close to him.
當時他應該也希望 我能默默陪在他身邊吧？
It was a long time ago.
不過，都是好久以前的事了
It was nice talking to you.
能跟妳聊聊真是太好了
Me too.
我也是
Why did you come? I told you that this is my business.
妳怎麼來了？ 我不是說這是我自己的事嗎？
I will not disturb you.
我又不會礙著你
Don't say unnecessary things.
別說多餘的話喔
Stay silent the whole time.
絕對要保持沉默
Yes, sir.
遵命
Tokyo Daiichi Bank here to see you.
東京第一銀行的職員想見你
-Let them in right away. -Okay.
-讓他們進來吧 -好的
Soma.
相馬？
I thought Mr. Matsuki had come.
我還以為是松木先生呢
Why?
你怎麼來了？
Tokyo Daiichi Bank can't finance Digital Blue.
東京第一銀行 是不會給藍色數位融資的
What are you talking about?
你這是在說什麼啊？
Mr. Matsuki told me
松木先生跟我說
that the loan screening was moving along.
融資審查很順利呢
What's wrong, Soma?
怎麼了，相馬？
Aoi…
青井
if you were worrying about something, would you tell me?
如果你有什麼煩心事的話 可以跟我說啊
What are you talking about?
你到底在說什麼啊？
I am not worrying about anything.
我沒什麼煩心事啊
I will listen to your problems if your company is in trouble.
如果你的公司陷入困境的話 我會盡力幫你的
It's the bank's job to offer advice at a time like this.
銀行的職責就是在這種時期給予意見
I know that you are a competent banker.
我知道你是個很優秀的銀行職員
But we don't need your help.
不過，我這裡不需要你的意見
We have no problem. Everything is going pretty well.
我們沒陷入什麼困境，一切都很順利
Then why?
那是為什麼呢？
Why did you manipulate the financial statement?
為什麼你要偽造財務報告？
What did you say?
你說什麼？
Aoi.
青井
I can imagine that it is lonely being a business manager.
我知道打理一家企業是很孤獨的
I'm sure it's hard to find someone you can openly talk to.
很難找到能說心裡話的對象
But…
可是
I'm your friend, right?
我是你的朋友啊
Whatever problem you have,
無論你遇到什麼問題
please tell me the truth.
不能對我說真話嗎？
I see.
原來如此
You knew everything, huh?
你全都知道了
Soma.
相馬
I'm sorry.
對不起
As you know, I was trying to deceive you for money.
我的確是為了錢，想要騙你
I've done something I shouldn't have.
我做了絕不能被原諒的事
I'm sorry.
對不起
But…
但是
I really need money for the company.
為了公司，我真的很需要這筆資金
Can't you turn a blind eye, for old times' sake?
看在我們老交情的分上 你能不能當作不知道？
You're the only one I can ask for help.
這件事我只能拜託你了
If not 500 million, how about 100 million?
五億不行的話，一億也可以
No, even 50 million.
不然，五千萬也可以
-Stop it, Aoi. -Soma, I promise that I will return it.
-夠了，青井 -相馬，我保證我一定會還的
Soma…
相馬
Please… I beg you…
拜託，我求你了
That's enough.
你適可而止吧
Don't you understand that Mr. Soma is suffering?
你不知道相馬也很難受嗎？
What do you know?
-花咲 -妳懂什麼？
Soma and I are old friends.
我和相馬是老朋友了
With all due respect…
恕我直言
if you are his old friend, why can't you understand his feelings?
身為老朋友的你 怎麼就不明白相馬的心情呢？
Mr. Soma is suffering because you are his friend.
相馬就是因為你是老朋友 才會那麼難受
Hanasaki, shut up.
花咲，別說了
No, I won't!
我不要！
Mr. Aoi.
青井先生
Mr. Soma is trying to take responsibility for everything.
相馬要準備一個人負起所有責任
He is a victim of fraud,
明明自己也是被騙的那個
but he is trying so hard
卻竭盡全力
to prevent you from being charged with a criminal offense.
袒護著你，讓你免於刑事處罰
I am very sorry.
真的非常抱歉
Headquarters…
他去了總部
I will take all responsibility.
我會負起所有責任
…And the Gotanda Branch…
還去了五反田分行
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
…He went to those places to apologize.
他到處鞠躬致歉，說是自己的錯
He did so because
他會這麼做
you are his precious friend.
就是因為你是他很珍惜的朋友
Because you are his friend that he trusted.
是值得他信任的朋友
It's wrong for you to deceive and use Mr. Soma
你為了錢欺騙他、利用他
in order to get money out of him.
這是不對的
It's wrong!
這是大錯特錯
Was your friendship
對你來說
with Mr. Soma nothing more than this?
跟相馬的友情就那麼不值錢嗎？
Hanasaki, that's enough.
花咲，夠了
Sorry.
對不起
Soma…
相馬
-Mr. Soma! -Mr. Matsuki.
-相馬先生 -松木先生
I got something.
我發現了一件事
Mr. Aoi is borrowing money from several financial institutions.
青井先生跟好幾家金融機構借了錢
One of them is troubling.
其中有一家有點麻煩
-Is that… -Yes. Loan sharks.
-難道是… -對，是高利貸
What happened, Aoi?
青井，這是怎麼回事？
Business started going down about two years ago.
大概兩年前，公司的業績漸漸下滑
I couldn't get a loan extension from the bank.
又得不到銀行的追加貸款
I was left with no choice.
我真的走投無路了
That's when a person I knew introduced me to a company that lends money,
那時有個熟人跟我說 有一家公司願意借錢給我們
and I jumped at it.
我就馬上借了錢
But…
但是…
Here it is, Mr. Aoi.
給你，青井先生
…I found out later…
我之後才發現…
Please confirm.
請確認
…That the company was…
原來那家公司是…
Loan sharks?
是高利貸？
At first, I was planning to repay them right away.
我一開始想要立刻還錢
But I got deeper and deeper in debt.
但欠款卻越滾越多
And my wife is the joint guarantor.
而我的妻子是連帶保證人
They said that if I can't repay,
他們說如果我再不還錢
my family will not be safe.
就對我家人不客氣
That's when I saw you at the reunion.
我就是那時，在校友會見到你
I had no time to be attending a party,
我本來是沒時間參加什麼聚會的
but I was able to turn back time for a while.
但那時想說可以重返當年的時光
It was fun.
我真的很開心
But after that…
只是在那之後…
Tokyo Daiichi Bank, huh?
東京第一銀行啊
Mr. Aoi, you have a good friend.
青井先生的朋友都是了不起的人物呢
Let's borrow money from him since he is your old classmate.
既然是老同學的話 你可以向他借錢啊
No. I can't cause him any trouble.
不行，我不能給那傢伙添麻煩
Don't you understand your situation?
你現在的立場有資格說這些嗎？
Deceive him and get 500 million yen from him.
找那傢伙騙五億日元出來就沒事了
Do you understand?
聽懂了沒啊？
So you followed his order.
於是你就聽了他的話？
I planned to repay all the money I borrowed from Tokyo Daiichi Bank,
我原本打算向東京第一銀行 借五億日元用來還債
and make my company go bankrupt with a debt of 500 million yen.
然後讓公司揹著五億的債款宣佈破產
That was the scenario.
這就是我的計畫
I…
我…
I really wanted to protect my family, no matter what.
我無論如何都想保護我的家人
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
I'm over.
我完蛋了
You are not over yet.
還沒結束呢
SHIROYAMA FINANCE
（白山金融機構）
Who are you?
你誰啊？
I am Soma from Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
我是東京第一銀行的相馬
What does a bank want from us?
銀行的人找我們有何貴幹啊？
I came here as an agent for Aoi of Digital Blue.
我今天是代表 藍色數位公司的青井先生前來
Tokyo Daiichi Bank examined
東京第一銀行
the loan application of 500 million yen for Digital Blue
審查了藍色數位公司 高達五億日元的融資申請
and decided to turn it down.
並且決定拒絕該申請
That has nothing to do with us.
這跟我們有什麼關係啊？
It sure does.
當然有關係了
This is a very important document.
這是一份非常重要的文件
Shouichi Aoi, the President of Digital Blue
藍色數位公司的社長青井省一
filed for voluntary bankruptcy.
已經申請了自願破產
What?
什麼？
COMMENCEMENT OF BANKRUPTCY PROCEEDINGS
（破產程序正式生效，青井省一）
From now on, please refrain from contacting him and his family.
今後 請不要再接觸青井先生及其家人
What are you talking about?
-你說什麼呢？
One more thing.
還有一件事
Precisely speaking, what you did was blackmail and fraud.
嚴格來說 你們的所作所為屬於勒索和詐騙
We will also take legal action, depending on your future actions.
我們會根據你日後的行為 考慮採取法律行動
Please be aware.
請你警惕
I hope Mr. Soma is okay.
相馬沒問題吧？
He's back.
啊，出來了
-Mr. Soma!
-相馬 -相馬先生
Are you okay?
你還好吧？
That was so scary.
嚇死我了
They pulled no punches.
那群傢伙可都是來真的
It's because you went all by yourself.
還不是因為你要自己一個人去
She is right.
就是說啊
If I had known, I should have asked you to go in place of me.
早知道那麼可怕 我應該叫妳去就好了
-What do you mean? Not Mr. Matsuki? -What? No way.
-什麼意思？你應該叫松木先生吧？ -什麼？我不行啦
Hey!
喂
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花咲居酒屋）
I wonder how Mr. Aoi is doing.
不知道青井先生怎麼樣了
He said he would start all over and work hard.
他說他會重頭開始，努力奮鬥呢
I see.
這樣啊
He has a family, so he has to protect them no matter what.
畢竟他還有無論如何 都想要好好守護的家人啊
Although that doesn't justify everything.
不過，也不能不擇手段啦
Yes. Women become strong when they have something to protect,
是啊，女人有了想保護的東西 就會變得更堅強
as opposed to men, who become weak when they have something to protect.
可是，男人反而會變得更脆弱呢
He was building not only his career, but also a happy family.
不過，他也算是創過業 還組織了一個幸福的家庭啊
I couldn't do any of them.
我一樣都沒做好
So I wanted to prevent his family from breaking apart.
所以，我才想幫他維繫他的家庭啊
It's nice to have that kind of friendship.
有這樣的兄弟情真棒啊
There will come a day when you can laugh about this over some drinks.
總有一天你們會一起喝著酒 笑著回憶這件事情的
I hope so.
希望如此吧
By the way, she was really sweet.
話說回來，她真的是個很好的人啊
I mean Yumi.
我說由美小姐
What are you bringing her up all of a sudden?
妳怎麼突然說這個啊？
It's too bad she got remarried.
真可惜她再婚了呢
I don't feel bad about that at all.
我可是一點都不覺得可惜
-Do you still love her? -Don't be stupid.
-你還喜歡她嗎？ -別說傻話
-It may be Yumi. -No way.
-可能是由美小姐打來的 -不可能啦
How come she's so sharp sometimes?
這傢伙有時怎麼那麼敏銳啊？
Mai. I have a watermelon. Help me cut it.
小舞，我這裡有個西瓜，幫我切吧
Okay.
好的
Hello, what's up?
喂？怎麼了？
I heard about Aoi from Saori.
我從紗織那裡聽說了青井的事
It must have been tough.
好像很嚴重呢
Apparently, Aoi is consolidating his company's debts
青井現在一邊整理公司的債務
while going around places to apologize.
一邊忙著四處謝罪
I see.
原來如此
He still has lots of things to do.
他還有很多爛攤子要收拾呢
Aoi should be fine.
青井一定沒問題的
He established his company from scratch.
那家公司也是他白手起家的
He can do anything now.
現在的他什麼都能做成的
Saori says she will support him with the children.
紗織也說會和孩子們一起支持他
That's good for him.
這樣他就更有動力了
I'm sorry that I couldn't support you.
抱歉，我無法在你身邊支持你
When you had a really hard time.
在你最低潮的時候
When you were depressed saying that your life as a banker had ended.
在你消沉地說 你的銀行職業生涯要結束的時候
I stepped away from you.
我離開了你
It was my bad.
那是我不好
But you got over it. You have changed.
不過，你還是熬過去了 還變了不少呢
Changed? Have I?
我變了不少嗎？
It's either your current job suits you very well,
是因為你很喜歡現在的工作
or is it because of Ms. Hanasaki?
還是因為花咲小姐她呢？
What are you talking about?
妳說什麼呢？
She is always causing me trouble.
那傢伙只會給我添麻煩
Take care of yourself.
那你保重哦
You too. Take care.
妳也是，保重
Here it comes. It's ready.
好了，西瓜切好了
-Let's eat. -It looks delicious.
-來吃吧 -看起來好好吃
-We need salt. -Thank you.
-要拿鹽 -謝謝
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
My grandma told me to face east and laugh before eating the first fruit
我奶奶曾經告訴我 吃當季的第一種水果時要面向東邊
of the season.
大笑之後再吃
-What? -Didn't you know that?
-什麼？ -你們沒聽說過嗎？
Let's do it together.
那我們一起吧
Let's eat it.
-我開動了
There was trouble in the Gotanda Branch.
五反田分行好像出了點問題啊
The news reached you too, Executive Director Shindo?
真藤常務，您也聽說了嗎？
I heard that Branch Inspection was involved again.
我聽說又跟分行稽核班有關啊？
Yes.
是的
They probably wanted to create results by making a big loan contract,
他們好像是想搞定一筆巨額融資 立下大功
but they ended up causing lots of trouble for everyone.
結果卻給大家添了不少麻煩
They really don't know their place.
他們真的是不懂分寸啊
If I remember correctly, you and Soma are colleagues, right?
我沒記錯的話 那個相馬好像跟你是同一期的吧？
Yes.
是的
I will make sure to tell him
我會去警告他
not to exceed the responsibilities of a Branch Inspector.
不要再插手分行稽核班分外的事情
It seems like he's a man with a backbone.
看來，他真的是個有骨氣的男人呢
-What? -Huh?
-什麼？ -嗯？
Nothing.
沒什麼
I am very sorry for causing you trouble, Mr. Shibasaki.
很抱歉這次給你添麻煩了，芝崎次長
Not at all.
沒什麼啦
In the end, our bank didn't have to suffer any loss.
銀行最終也沒什麼損失
I'm glad.
真是萬幸呢
I'd understand it if it was Ms. Hanasaki,
不過，要是發生在花咲身上 我還能理解
but I didn't expect Mr. Soma to cause a problem.
沒想到居然是相馬你惹出禍來
I'd understand if it was Ms. Hanasaki.
要是花咲的話，我還能理解
Old men are so disorganized.
大叔還真是邋遢啊
Good morning.
早安
Mr. Matsuki, good morning.
松木先生，早安
Mr. Soma hasn't come in yet.
相馬還沒來呢
-Ms. Hanasaki. I did it. -Yes.
-花咲小姐，我做到了 -是
-You did what? -A new loan contract.
-做到什麼？ -新的融資業務啊
Oh, really?
真的嗎？
It's a vegetable store in the shopping district.
對啊，是商店街的一家蔬菜店
It is not as big as Digital Blue,
雖然不是藍色數位那種規模的公司
but I realized that I prefer supporting smaller businesses
但我還是覺得 我比較想要幫助這些小型企業
even if that means dealing with less money.
就算金額比較小也無所謂
That's great. Congratulations.
那真是太好了，恭喜你
Thank you very much.
謝謝妳
Ms. Hanasaki.
那個…花咲小姐
Yes?
是
To celebrate the new loan,
為了慶祝我拿下新業務…
would you like to join me?
妳要不要一起去？
GRILLED MEAT
（明祿苑烤肉）
I wanted to go to this restaurant.
我一直想去這家餐廳呢
How did you get this?
你是怎麼拿到的？
Oh, I just happened to get it from someone.
剛好有人給我的
I was hoping we could go out with just the two of us…
我希望我們可以兩個人一起…
Good morning, Mr. Soma. Look at this.
早安，相馬，快看這個
Mr. Matsuki wants the three of us to celebrate his new contract.
松木先生說我們三個一起去這裡 慶祝他拿下新的融資業務
Not three, two.
不是三個人啦，是兩個
Great job, Matsuki.
幹得好啊，松木
-Thank you. -Look.
-謝謝 -你看
I wanted to go to this restaurant.
我正好想去這家餐廳呢
-It's three of us again. -I'm so excited.
-又是三個人啊？ -好期待啊
When will we go? How about tonight?
什麼時候去？不如就今晚吧
I am free, of course.
我當然沒問題了
And you, Mr. Matsuki?
松木先生呢？
-Yes. -That's cool.
-好啊 -真是太好了
I'm from the Inspection Unit.
我是檢查部的冰室
I won't lose.
我不會認輸的
Illegal credit inspection?
透過信用檢查進行不正當行為？
This is the bottom of Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
簡直是東京第一銀行最差勁的分行
We have to let them go scot-free?
只能放任他這麼做嗎？
People like you prevent this bank from improving.
就是因為有你這樣的人 這家銀行才沒辦法變好